Boluwatife Lambe

I am an experienced front-end developer with three years of experience creating visually appealing and user-friendly websites. I have extensive experience using React.js to develop efficient and responsive designs that enhance the performance of web applications along with a solid understanding of SEO techniques and best practices.

6, Ogunyemi Street
Somolu, Lagos
(+234) 8083 6475 31
boluwatifelambe@gmail.com
Portfolio:
https://lbdportfolio.netlify.ap

EXPERIENCE

Uptick Talent, Jos — Frontend Developer

Sep. 2023 - Dec. 2023

Transformed UI, UX, and business requirements into redefined code solutions.

Incorporated enhancements into web design to enhance user engagement, ensure seamless functionality, and optimize loading time.

Utilized React.js, Next.js, Typescript, and Javascript to implement features across both mobile and desktop platforms.

Collaborated with team members throughout the development process to validate creative proposals and ensure adherence to design best practices.

Conducted testing on web-based product functionality and implemented iterations.

Enoverlabs, Lagos — Frontend Developer (Intern)

Aug. 2023 - Nov. 2023

Successfully leading the front-end engineering team.

Maintaining and optimizing the codebase, resulting in improved performance.

Collaborating with the design team to implement new features and enhancements, resulting in a more user-friendly and visually appealing product.

Identifying and resolving bugs and issues, ensuring a seamless user experience.

Training and mentoring the subordinate frontend developer, enhancing their skills and productivity.

Contributed to developing a responsive and mobile-friendly website, improving accessibility for users across different devices.

Personally came up with new ideas and features that made the project stand out.

SKILLS

<u>p/</u>

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

React.js

Git

GitHub

Bootstrap

Next.js

Typescript

Node.js

Express.js

MongoDB

LANGUAGES

English, Spanish, Yoruba

EDUCATION

Lagos State University, Lagos, Nigeria — Diploma in Business Administration

March 2019 - April 2022

Achieved a graduation with a GPA of 4.6. Additionally, led a research project on "The Impact Of The External Environment On Small Scale Business Performance In Lagos State" as the primary researcher within a team.

AltSchool Africa, Lagos, Nigeria — Diploma in Software Engineering (Backend Development)

September 2023 - August 2024

Graduated with a strong understanding of backend development and a focus on building scalable, secure systems. Built a full-stack capstone project "Eventful", a dynamic platform that goes beyond ticketing by curating various experiences—from concerts and theater performances to sports events and cultural gatherings. Built using Node.js and MongoDB, the system supports secure user authentication and efficient event management.

EXTRA INFORMATION

Secured the second position among 32 participants in a front-end development competition organized by Dominion Computer College.

Actively contributed to various collaborative projects and maintained a portfolio of personal side projects as well as open-source projects.

Completed the Openclassroom course on web development.

Additionally, received a certificate of appreciation for teaching web development to students in an NGO.

A postman student expert.